KYAW YE THU

Yuseong-gu, Daejeon, South Korea

८+82 10-5165-7883 ♦ **A**kyawyethu@kaist.ac.kr ♦ **in**linkedin.com/in/kyaw-ye-thu **Q**github.com/KyawYeThu-11 ♦ **S**kyawyethu.wixsite.com/portfolio

PERSONAL PROFILE

A sophomore studying computer science and business & technology management. With expertise gained from my formal study, my ambition is to do research about intelligence in machines as well as work on improving the quality and delivery of education in the modern age by technical and social approaches. In this respect, I have worked on the delivery of computer science education to children in Myanmar by teaching them online and contributing to the curriculum at a social enterprise.

EDUCATION

Korea Advanced Institute of Science and Technology (KAIST)
School of Computing

August 2022 - Present

- Major in Computer Science, Minor in Business and Technology Management
- Welfare Member of KAIST International Student Association (KISA)
- Futsal Division Head of ASCEND (Multi-sports Student Club)
- CGPA: 3.52 of 4.3

Practising High School, Yangon University of Education

June 2008 - March 2020

- Conferred *The Whole Burma Ninth* for being the ninth highest achiever in the 2019-2020 Myanmar Matriculation Exam among about one million students
- Selected as a participant for Myanmar Mathematical Olympiad (National Level)

PUBLICATIONS

[1] **Kyaw Ye Thu**, Nguyen T.L, Rajabova K., Kumar S., Nguyen N.M, "Advanced Passage Retrieval with Lexical and Semantic Matching", 2023

PROJECTS

- [1] **PlayMath**. A playground where you can interact with widgets to solidify your mathematical understanding
- [2] **Third Eye**. A free online tool that aims to offer various computer vision services. Currently though, there is only one functionality available, object detection. Using our tool, you can detect objects from videos and photos in real time or asynchronously.
- [3] **Burmese G2P**. Myanmar (Burmese) Language Grapheme to Phoneme Converter for automatic speech recognition (ASR) and text-to-speech (TTS)
- [4] **Space Invaders**. A classic arcade style 2D shooting game wherein the player spaceship shoots at the enemies and bosses while avoiding their attacks.

RELEVANT COURSES TAKEN FROM KAIST

- Introduction to Programming (CS101) Discrete Mathematics (CS204) Data Structure (CS206)
- Computer Organization (CS311) Intro to Software Engineering (CS350) Intro to Deep Learning (CS371) Intro to AI (CS470) Graph Machine Learning and Mining (CS471) Intro to Intelligent Robotics (CS477)

WORK EXPERIENCE

KAIST Language Center

February 2023 - November 2023

South Korea Part-time

English Conversation Tutor. Help a Korean public official foster English speaking skill by having one-on-one English conversations with him

KAIST School of Digital Humanities

June 2023 - December 2023

South Korea Part-time

English Teaching Assistant. Assisted a professor in charge of English writing courses with grading and administering the classes.

Simbolo June 2022

Myanmar Project-based

Curriculum Developer. Constructed a curriculum of an introductory artificial intelligence course for teenagers

Thate Pan Hub x Spring University

March 2022

Myanmar

Project-based

Data Science Instructor. Trained people from various parts of Myanmar about SAP analytics cloud for data science applications. Promoted ASEAN Data Science Explorer competition.

SOCIAL CONTRIBUTION

ASCEND January 2024 - Present

Multi-sports Student Club in KAIST

Futsal Division Head. Ensured the members can play weekly futsal matches conveniently

KAIST International Student Association (KISA)

February 2023 - December 2023

The ISA of KAIST

Welfare Division Member.

- Contributed to the preparation and operation of various events and welfare programs for KAIST international students
- Led a futsal tournament within the university for the Sports Festival

Thate Pan Hub

November 2021 - May 2022

A non-profit educational social enterprise in Myanmar

Teacher.

- Administered and taught computer science and artificial intelligence classes for young teenagers of age 10-13
- Led the Teaching and Development sub-unit of the AI team and contributed to the AI curriculum
- Helped organize a national hackathon, named 'Hub&Hack', for teenagers around Myanmar

Zee Kwat Academy

July 2021 - July 2022

A sister organization of Thate Pan Hub for formal education

Science and Technology Club Co-leader. Shared knowledge about science and computer technology with children while exposing them with science-related activities to foster their enthusiasm in science and technology

SKILLS AND RESEARCH INTEREST

Technical Skills Python, Javascript, Java, C, HTML, CSS

Tensorflow, Pytorch, Django

Git, Linux

Misc. Public speaking, Teaching, Academic Research

LanguagesBurmese (Native), English (C2), Korean (Elementary)Research InterestsArtificial General Intelligence, Human-AI Interaction,

Computer Science Education, Collaborative Learning